## Gamachis Yadesa

10049 Ives Way, Maple Grove, MN 55369 gyadesa@gmail.com | 612-481-9934 | Maple Grove, Minnesota

LinkedIn: <a href="https://linkedin.com/in/gamachis-yadesa">https://linkedin.com/in/gamachis-yadesa</a> | Github: <a href="https://github.com/gyadesa">https://github.com/gyadesa</a> | Website: <a href="https://gyadesa.github.io">https://gyadesa.github.io</a>

## **Professional Summary**

Full Stack Web Developer with over 8 years of experience in Software Quality Assurance Life Cycle. Solid history of discovering errors, resolving defects, and ensuring client expectations are met with high quality software solutions. Ability to easily collaborate with developers and project managers to accomplish milestones using agile methodologies is practiced.

## **Technical Summary**

- HTML5/CSS/JavaScript
- QTP/UFT/Lean FT
- MySQL queries
- Quality assurance
- Test case development
- Documentation
- Agile/Scrum expertise
- DOORS/TFS

- Bootstrap
- Regression testing
- Selenium
- Version One
- Process improvements
- Team player
- Cucumber/SpecFlow
- GIT/Jenkins/Subversion

## **Projects**

• Projects worked on are listed at - my portfolio project site or my github project address

## **Professional Experience**

#### **Self-Employed**

University of Minnesota

May 2018 to Current

- Coding boot Camp. Full Stack dynamic end-to-end web app course.
- Executed YouTube search functionality, embedded videos using the YouTube API, Firebase, JavaScript, jQuery, and HTML5.
- Developed original creative solutions for marketing objectives, while maintaining creative, technical and brand standards.

#### YBS Solutions, LLC.

Oct 2017- Current

Web Developer

- Completed digital projects sorting algorithms that updated in real-time as new filter parameters were selected; sole developer on the project.
- Developed a dynamic driven solutions database using JavaScript; increased user clicks by 65%.

#### **Baxter Healthcare**

Jul 2017 - Oct 2017

Senior Software Verification and Validation Engineer (Consultant)

- Performed system verification and test validation process of acute and dialysis infusion systems and devices
- Reviewed verification and validation test cases and software test documentation
- Designed test plans and test cases for Dialyses therapeutic renal care system
- Designed test simulator test scripts using Python programming language
- Used HP ALM and DOORS for Software Test application planning, documentation, and tracking
- Used JIRA for bug-reporting, tracking, and reviewing defects
- Designed, developed, and supported an end to end smoke test automation of infusion system application.

#### **Gamachis Yadesa**

#### SMITHS Medical Jun 2012 – Jun 2017 Senior Software Automation Engineer (Consultant) (Aug 2015 – Jun 2017)

- Designed and developed of PharmGuard (Health Care Management System) smoke Test automation.
- Designed, developed, and supported end to end smoke test automation of infusion system application.
- Gained working knowledge of common automation frameworks such as SpecFlow, UFT and LeanFT.
- Conducted continuous integration, continuous delivery and reported daily build results to developers.
- Ensured MS updates on Smoke Test VM servers were up-to-date
- Updated and ensured daily smoke test automation codes were current and up-to-date with daily application changes
- Configured and supported SSIS, SMO and CLR components of the SQL Server components for reports
- Analyzed system compatibility and speed requirements for systems performance tests
- Reported and reviewed defects using MS Team Foundation Server (TFS)

#### **Senior Software Tester (Consultant)**

(Jun 2012 – Jul 2015)

- Test lead, designing test cases
- Coordinated with project management to understand client specifications
- Worked with developers to track backlog items
- Spearhead planning procedures for team
- Supported product rollouts across multiple code releases
- Set prioritization of module testing
- Oversaw team work and assigned different testing tasks
- Created test cases for new product development
- Worked with on-and off-site quality assurance teams to coordinate testing
- Continuously updated testing documentation
- Provided QA feedback for review retrospectives
- Ensured documentation met quality standards as well as completeness of software validation records
- Supported and complied with FDA regulations (510(k)) in all R&D testing

# Fluke Thermography Software Tester

Feb 2011 - Jun 2012

- Responsible for designing test cases and scenarios for usability testing
- Updated testing documentation for new hires
- Received and interpreted product owner specifications
- Performed compatibility and continues improvement of legacy product testing
- Tested a leading-edge thermograph imager and supported software application tool
- Generated and analyzed resultant radiometric sounds, videos, and standard image files

#### SMITHS Medical Aug 2008 – Feb 2011

#### Firmware Verification and Validation Engineer (Consultant)

- Performed Embedded Software Testing, Verification and Validation of drug infusion medical device with the integration of SDLS/STLC and applying principles of FDA regulations
- Calibrated and tested hardware and firmware in a medical drug infusion device
- Fully complied with FDA regulations (510(k)) in all R&D testing

### **Gamachis Yadesa**

- Installed embedded software releases and performed white box tests
- Wrote and maintained SQL scripts for data transfer and analysis from the device to a server
- Validated both cable and wireless (802.11 b/g) data transfers; S-HTTP and SSL protocols
- Analyzed device electromagnetic immunity
- Collaborated in the documentation of QA test plans (integration, validation, and regression)
- Assisted in the establishment of test process methodology and defect report design
- Utilized tools for requirement tracking (Doors), Defect reporting (Mantis), Software Source control (SVN), and Documentation Control (Pilgrim)

Seagate Jan 2008 – Jun 2008 System Integration and Firmware Test Engineer (Consultant)

- Served as system Integration Engineer and Firmware Test Engineer
- Wrote and executed test protocols for quality verification of Enterprise Drive Firmware (SATA, SAS and Fiber Channel)
- Analyzed and reported test results for software continuation effort, including corrective action recommendations

DataCard Group Software Test Engineer

Dec 2001 - Oct 2007

- Designed, developed and documented software components of products that met internal and external customer specified requirements in a timely fashion and with a high level of quality
- Wrote and maintained build and test scripts for print driver applications
- Developed software drivers for secure identification card printers
- Worked with Visual Studio.NET C, C++, C# and Visual Basic for application development, SDK application and printer driver development
- Assisted in \$1M cost reduction via the development of a print driver user interface in nine international languages
- Designed and integrated a diagnostic tool for driver development
- Wrote and executed project test plans and their associated test cases for all test phases;
  integration, functional and system test
- Reviewed plans with hardware and software development engineering teams
- Specified and maintained applicable test environments

#### **Education**

University of Minnesota. St. Paul, MN Full-stack Flex Coding Boot camp

May 2018 - Present

University of St. Thomas. St. Paul, MN

Jan 2003 - May 2006

Master of Science, Software Engineering and Database Management

Minnesota State University. Mankato, MN

Jan 1996 - May 2000

Bachelor of Science, Computer Information Systems and Software Management Systems